

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, DATA SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING STUDENT · MASTER'S STUDENT

🛘 (+216) 21218835 🗷 mohamedtaiebslama@gmail.com 🅱 taiebslama.live 📠 mohamedtaiebslama 🤾 taieb_slama

Heavily passionate about Game Programming, Artificial Intelligence and Data Engineering, I am creative and work well in teams. I also have experience working on DevOps, Web and Mobile Development. I am currently on the lookout for a 4-6 months End of Studies Internship.

Education

Bachelor in Software Engineering, Data Science and Engineering

Tunisia

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF APPLIED SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (INSAT)

Sep. 2017 - Present

· Courses: Data Science, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Big Data, Software Architecture and Design, Software Development and Quality, DevOps, Parallel Computing, Formal Languages and Compilation, Blockchain, Security, Distributed Systems, etc...

Master's Degree (M2) in Information Processing and Complexity of Living Systems

Tunisia

NATIONAL ENGINEERING SCHOOL OF TUNIS (ENIT)

Sep. 2021 - Present

· Courses: 3D Images, Image Segmentation, Video Analysis, Perceptual Aspects in Audio Processing, Audio Signal Processing and Learning Algorithms, Random Signal Representation, Complex Dynamical Systems, Estimation and Detection, Machine Learning, etc...

Skills

Programming Languages C#, C++, Python, R, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Dart, Java

Frameworks & Technologies .NET, Unity, Angular, ReactJS, NodeJS, NestJS, Laravel, Flask, Flutter, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Other Used Tools Jupyter, GitLab, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Unreal Engine, Blender, Linux, Apache, Nginx, Jira

Spoken Languages English: Professional Proficiency | French: Native | Arabic: Native | German: Elementary Proficiency

Professional Experience

Data Science Intern Tunisia

EXPENSYA June 2021 - Sep. 2021

- · Worked on a feature allowing users to Fast Scan their Vehicle Registration Documents to automatically create new Vehicles with the needed data. I also wrote the necessary Tests to ensure my work is functional while keeping the Code Coverage high.
- Used Technologies: .NET and C# using Visual Studio, SQL Database, AngularJS, SonarQube, Git and Azure Devops.

Part-time FullStack Developer and DevOps Engineer

Tunisia

INFRAPLUS

Nov. 2020 - May 2021

- This Part-time job consisted mainly in migrated the website worked on during the Internship from a Monolithic Architecture to a Microservices Architecture.
- Used Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Nginx webserver, Kong Gateway, Linux and Jira.

FullStack Developer and DevOps Intern

Tunisia

INFRAPLUS

May 2020 - Oct. 2020

- · Contributed in creating a Website where companies can post their internship opportunities and students can browse them and send
- Used Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Linux and Jira.

Other Projects _

Mud Monster Game While making this pixel art game, I tried going through as many Game Development phases as possible: I set the world (lore and character designs), created my own sprites, animated them, designed the level, implemented objects, programmed the game controls and rules. It was a simple project but I was very satisfied with what I learnt.

Fuzzy Isolation Forest A Data Science Research Project aiming to study the Isolation Forest Algorithm and its anomaly isolation, then compare how efficient this approach is when dealing with Fuzzy data and rules instead of the classic Crisp data.

Website of the Fédération Tunisienne d'Athlétisme (FTA) This Federation represents the Tunisian Athletes. For that matter, my team and I created a website showcasing the Tunisian sports industry achievements and athletes, the different sport categories and leagues, and the federation services.

Extracurricular Activity _____

2020 - 2021	Head of Project Department, Junior Entreprise INSAT	INSAT
2020	1st Place , HackUp Fin'Hack Hackathon	Tunisia
2019 - 2020	Volunteer, AIESEC LC University	Tunisia
2017 - 2021	Member and Webmaster, ACM INSAT Student Chapter	INSAT